## Antonio De Luca - Software Developer, Architect and Entrepreneur

https://www.antoniodeluca.info - contact@antoniodeluca.info - CV updated to 01 Jul 2020

## Summary

An highly skilled **Full Stack** developer with strong preference for the **Front End**.

Fanatic of Minimalist Software Development, Accurate Database Design and Meticulous Business Analysis. Specialized in but not limited to Web Applications. Focused on Functional and Reactive paradigms as well as on Event Driven and Service Oriented architectures. Strongly experienced in Object Oriented programming.

I've studied electronics, written my first code on a VIC 20 and, during 1999, finally understood that software development was my future. After that, during ~21 years, I've worked in various contexts developing applications for web as well as for other purposes with JavaScript and many other programming languages.

Software is my passion and a lot of my time is spent around it.

# **Principal Skills**

# Recapped

JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, FP, OOP, RP, Test Driven Development (TDD).

#### Detailed

Client languages: JavaScript, TypeScript

Client libraries: React.

Server languages: JavaScript, TypeScript

Server libraries: Express, Next.js.

Other notable libraries: MobX, Ramda, RxJS, styled-components.

<u>Testing tools</u>: **Chai**, Cypress, Enzyme, Jest, **Karma**, **Mocha**, Nightwatch.js, React Testing Library,

Sinon.is, WebdriverIO.

<u>Automation tools</u>: **Babel**, ESLint, Flow, **Gulp**, JSDoc, PostCSS, Prettier, stylelint, TSLint, **Webpack**.

<u>Programming paradigms</u>: Functional (FP), Object Oriented (OOP), Reactive (RP).

<u>Strategies</u>: Acceptance Test Driven Development (ATDD), Behaviour Driven Development (BDD), Data Transaction oriented development, Design Pattern oriented development, Domain Driven Design (DDD), Iterative refactoring, Rapid prototyping, Test Driven Development (TDD), The London School of TDD (Outside-In).

Architectures: Event Driven, Microfrontends, Microservices, Service Oriented.

<u>Web service protocols</u>: **REST**, SOAP, XML-RPC. <u>Data presentation languages</u>: **CSS**, **HTML**. <u>Data interchange formats</u>: **JSON**, XML, YAML.

<u>Data extraction languages</u>: **Regular Expressions**, **SQL**.

<u>Database engines</u>: MongoDB, **MySQL**.

Cloud services: AWS.

<u>Application servers/Run-time environments/Web servers</u>: NGINX, **Node.js**.

<u>Collaboration methodologies</u>: Kanban, Mob Programming, **Pair Programming**, **Scrum**.

<u>Version control systems</u>: **Git**, SVN. <u>Modelling notations</u>: **ERD**, UML. <u>Dependencies managers</u>: **npm**, Yarn.

<u>Known concerns</u>: Accessibility, Database reliability (constraints, normalization, replication, sharding), Internationalization, Application security (SQL injection, code injection, session hijacking, cookies manipulations), Scalability.

<u>Other</u>: Bash scripting, CircleCI, Docker, Docker Compose, Docker Swarm, GitLab CI/CD, Linux, OSX, Serverless, Shell commands, SonarQube, Terraform, Travis CI, Vagrant, Windows.

# **Experiences**

# Cazoo (10/2019 - present) | https://www.cazoo.co.uk - London (UK)

Senior Software Developer (mainly for Web Applications)

In this company I am:

- Developing on Backend as well as on Frontend.
- · Helping with technical interviews.
- Doing internal talks on topics of shared interest.

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript

## DAZN (08/2016 – 02/2019) | https://www.dazn.com - London (UK)

<u>Principal Software Developer</u> [Apr. 2017 / Feb. 2019] (mainly for Web Applications) after having been <u>Senior Software Developer</u> [Aug. 2016 / Mar. 2017]

In this company I have:

- Designed and implemented, within a team and under the Architect supervision, an high
  performance Microfrontends bootstrapper able to change SPAs without any page reload, to do
  custom caching of the downloaded SPAs, to allow reactive intercommunication between the SPAs,
  to act as a lightweight hidden background controller and to be the single entry point for all the
  target devices supported by the company product through HTML/CSS/JS clients.
- Designed and implemented, within a team and under the Architect supervision, a custom CI/CD system, based on the "Infrastructure as Code" paradigm, able to run pipelines of intercommunicating tasks through isolated containers. After only ~3 months the system started to allow a growing number of teams to have static analysis, complex custom building processes, tests suites and more automatically executed for them as well as to be able to autonomously manage their pipelines.
- Designed and implemented, within a team and under the Architect supervision, many high scalability pipelines through the use of a mix of the custom CI/CD system, AWS Lambdas and local devices connected via VPN.
- Achieved, within a team and under the Architect supervision, a successful ~2 months fast prototype implementation of the company Microfrontends architecture proposal.
- Contributed to the implementation of the video player component.
- Contributed, with design validation and code reviewing, to the implementation of the company Microfrontends architecture as well as of many of the related SPAs.
- Contributed, together other Principal Developers and Architects, to the standards and best practices definitions, the supporting and mentoring of Junior as well as Senior Developers, the leading of various teams and the interviewing processes.

Programming Languages: JavaScript

#### Access (08/2015 – 08/2016) | https://www.theaccessgroup.com - London (UK)

Senior Software Developer (mainly for Web Applications)

In this company I have been in charge for the design and development of the frontend side application (AngularJS) of one of their mainstream solutions. The same project involved me as an additional senior developer for code reviews about the server side application (LAMP based API). Previously I have also worked on the design and development of the frontend side application (AngularJS) of another one of their mainstream solutions. I have also been involved in the development of a centralized logging system (Node.js based) and in the containerization of the development environments.

Programming Languages: JavaScript, PHP

IIT - Istituto Italiano di Tecnologia (07/2010 – 07/2015) | https://www.iit.it - Genova (GE) - Italy Lead Software Developer [Jul. 2014 – Jul. 2015] (mainly for Web Applications) after having been Senior Software Developer [Jul. 2010 – Jun. 2014]

In this research centre I have been in charge of the design and development of two projects, an internal proprietary (LAMP) scientific data analysis/reporting tool and the Open Source (MEAN) P2P "Scientilla" project. Often I also supported developers from various departments to decide the right architecture and appproach for their needs as well as to select the right web application frameworks, libraries, database

engines, server engines and other. I have also been involved in the management and development of various institutional web sites.

Programming Languages: C#, Java, JavaScript, PHP

## MIBATECH s.r.l. (09/2009 - 06/2010) | Fiumicino (RM) - Italy

Senior Software Developer (mainly for Web Applications)

In this company I have been in charge for the design and development of web applications for their network. I have also been responsible for the internal proprietary PHP framework and for C# based desktop applications.

Programming Languages: ActionScript, C#, JavaScript, PHP

## SWP - Software With Passion (01/2006 - 08/2009) | Pineto (TE) - Italy

Freelance Software Developer (mainly for Web Applications)

As a freelance consultant I have developed various websites based on Joomla!, with custom extensions implementation, as well as other minor applications based on C# and C/C++.

Programming Languages: C/C++, C#, JavaScript, PHP

#### NETRIX s.r.l. (09/2001 - 05/2007) | Pineto (TE) - Italy

Co-Founder & Software Developer (mainly for Web Applications)

In this company (closed in 2012) I have been in charge for the design and development of a public informative system distributed around cities over touch screen kiosks (INFOPoint City network) as well as for minor development activities on side works for little customers.

Programming Languages: C#, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Visual Basic

Various companies (09/1996 - 08/2001) - Minor experiences in terms of software development, while I was studying for my Computer Science Bachelor Degree course (that I have in the end abandoned), as well as other jobs outside the IT field.

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Perl, PHP

#### Certifications

CIW JavaScript Specialist (January 2015), Oracle Java SE 7 Programmer I (October 2014), Zend Certified PHP Engineer (March 2014), Zend Certified Engineer - PHP 5.3 (December 2013), Zend Certified Engineer - PHP 5 (May 2010).

......

......

#### Languages

English: Professional working proficiency - Italian: Native or bilingual proficiency.

#### Education

Industrial Electronics Technical Diploma (Sep. 1992 - Jul. 1996) - Istituto Tecnico Industriale "Vincenzo Cerulli" - Grade: 60/60

## References

Excellent - Some, public, available on my Linkedin page. Others, private, available under specific request.

# Other information

<u>Skype</u>: contact.antoniodeluca.info - <u>Residence</u>: London, United Kingdom - <u>Citizenship</u>: Italian - <u>Gender</u>: Male - <u>Birth year</u>: 1977 - <u>Availability to relocate</u>: No - <u>Availability to travel</u>: Yes - <u>Availability to work</u> remotely: Yes